A Guide to the Elden E. Billings Collection, 1862-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Elden E. Billings Collection, 1862-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1991-036
25.5 cu. ft. 22 boxes
This collection contains subject files, clippings, memorabilia and artifacts related to the American Civil War, collected by Elden E. Billings.
Billings, Elden E. (Collector)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Elden E. Billings Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1991 with additional materials added.
Scope and Content
This collection contains subject files, clippings, memorabilia and artifacts related to the American Civil War. There are seven series, five of which predominately contain Civil War materials. The other two series in the collection also contains files on other subjects of Billings' historical interests, including aspects of military and United States history.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series: Series I: Civil War Files and Prints; Series II: Other Subject Files; Series III: Lincoln Materials; Series IV: Elden E. Billings - Personel Files; Series V: Publications; Series VI: Primary Documents; and Series VII: Artifacts. Files in each series are arranged alphabetically by folder or item title.
Series I: Civil War Files and Prints contains subject files on various Civil War topics including specific battles, locations, regiments, and historic figures, as well as works of art, maps, and images. Other files include information on railroads, prisons, ethnic or social groups, and branches of the military.
Series II: Other Subject Files contains files on various topics, some tangentially related to the Civil War. Topics include, but are not limited to, figures from US military history, World Wars I and II, the Mexican War, railroads,
Series III: Lincoln Materials contains historical information about aspects of Lincoln's life and presidency. The series also includes cartoons, newsletters, portraits, and memorabilia.
Series IV: Elden E. Billings - Personal Files contains biographical information and photographs, correspondence to and from Billings, book catalogs, and notes relating to speaking events and writings.
Series V: Publications contains newsletters and journals, mostly from the Civil War period or about the Civil War. Other publications relate to Civil War Roundtables, historical societies, and military history.
Series VI: Primary Documents contains two subseries, Subseries A: Scrapbooks and Subseries B: Manuscripts. Subseries A: Scrapbooks includes several related to Civil War regiments or individuals. Subseries B: Manuscripts includes originals and typed copies of diaries, correspondence, and ephemera from the Civil War and Reconstruction periods.
Series VII: Artifacts contains several portraits, daguerrotypes, and photographs of Civil War figures, including Stonewall Jackson and Robert E. Lee. This series also contains medals, coins, calling cards, stamps, and other memorabilia. There are two non-Civil War related items: a print of an elephant fight from India, and a notebook that belonged to Ulysses S. Grant III.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
A portion of the Civil War books in the Special Collections Rare Book Collection were donated by Elden E. Billings. The department also houses a portrait of Elden E. "Josh" Billings.
Index Terms
Persons:
Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865
Subjects:
Civil War; Folk, historical, and patent medicine; Medicine; Medicine, Military--History; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- Series I: Civil War Files and Prints
  - Aeronautics, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alabama, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alton Union Riflers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Animals (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appomattox (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arkansas, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arms, Artillery, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Army of the Potomac (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 'Battles & Leaders' Project (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries A: Battles
    - Antietam, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Balls Bluff, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Big Bethel, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Brandy Station, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Brice Cross Roads, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Cedar Creek, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cedar Mtn., Battle of (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chantilly, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chattanooga, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chickamauga, Battle of (sketch on) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Clustee, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Cold Harbor, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Crater, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Fort Stedman, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Fort Stevens, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Galveston, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Gettysburg, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Manassas, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Pea Ridge, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Peninsula, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Pilot Knob, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Saltville, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Santa Rosa Island, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Spotsylvania Court House, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Vicksburg, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Wilderness, Battle of (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Wilderness, Battle of (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Bermuda, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bibliographies, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bierce, Gen. Lucius V. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bios, Various (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Black Troops (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - The Blue and the Gray, Curtis Paper Company, 4 black/white prints (Box 17)
  - Bragg, Brig. Gen. Braxton (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Brazil (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Brochures, Civil War parks/monuments/battlefields (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Brown, John (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Burnside, Gen. Ambrose (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Butler, Gen. Benjamin (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Campaigning with Lee Seminar (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Catton, Bruce (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Cavalry (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cemeteries (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Census Information (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Centennial, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Chamberlain, Gen. Joshua L. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Chaplains of the U. S. Army (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Christmas, Civil War (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Civil War, General Info (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Colonel Elmer E. Ellsworth, Currier & Ives print (Box 17)
  - Confederate Powder Works (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Conscription (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondents (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Currier & Ives prints – Genl. Beagher at the Battle of Fair Oaks, The storming of Fort Donelson, TN (Box 17)
  - Curtis, Josiah (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Davis, Jefferson (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Delaware, Civil War (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Derrickson, David V. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Douglas, Stephen (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Drummer Boys (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1899 picture of U.S. Grant (Box 17)
  - Ewing, Charles Brig. Gen. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fashion, Civil War-era (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Finance (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Flags (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Florida (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Affairs and the Civil War by Howard Westwood (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Forrest, Nathan Bedford (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Forts (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Georgia (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Generals (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gettysburg Address (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Gettysburg Advance and Retreat (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gettysburg Advance and Retreat (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Gettysburg, Commercial Tower Controversy (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gettysburg, Tourist Information (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Gibbons, Major General John (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Gill, Delancey W. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Grant, Gen. U.S. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Grout, Josuah, Publ., 1925 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "A Soldier's Tribute to His Chief" (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Guide of the Confederate Government, An Official" (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gulager, Charles (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hancock, Winfield Scott (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Harper's Ferry (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Hayes, Pres. Rutherford B. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Henderson, Gen. Thomas J. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hill, Gen. A. P. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hitchcock, Henry (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hooker, Gen. Joseph (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Hospitals (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Hunt, H. J. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hunter's Raid (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Illinois (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Indiana (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Intrenchment (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Iowa (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Irish (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Ironclads (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jackson, Gen. T. J. "Stonewall" (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jewish Servicemen (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Johnny Reb and Billy Yank" (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Kane, Brig. Gen (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Keene, Laura (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Keller, Cassius (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Kentucky (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Lee, Gen. R. E. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Lees of Virginia Tech (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lee Jackson Foundation (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Lee's General Order Number Nine, a likeness as a keepsake for the members of The Civil War Round Table (Box 17)
  - Longstreet, Lt. Gen James (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Loose pages from the Photographic History of the Civil War, 1910 by Brady (Box 14)
  - Louisiana (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Magruder, Gen. John B (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Maine (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Manassas, Mall Controversy (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Map, Lee Retreat/Appomattox Advance of (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Maps (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Maps (10) Second Battle of Manassas Troop Movements (Box 17)
  - Marine Corps (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Maryland (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Maury, Matthew Fontaine (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - McClellan, Gen. George B (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - McCook, Daniel (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meade, Gen. George (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Medicine (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Michigan (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Military Balls (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Military Order of the Loyal Legion – Memoriums (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mississippi (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Missouri (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Monitor, U.S.S (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Monuments, Civil War (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Music, Civil War Era (Box 3, Folder 19a?)
  - Navy (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - New Hampshire (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - New York (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - North Carolina (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Northern Lake Frontier during the Civil War", 1897 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Notes on Civil War, handwritten by Billings (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Ohio (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Oklahoma (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ord (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Gen. E. O. C., Career of – Thesis, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - People, Misc (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Personnel Problems (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Petersburg, VA – Siege of (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Phillips, David, Confederate Hero – copies (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Phoebus, Harrison (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs, Civil War calendar (Box 14)
  - Photographs – Civil War related (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs & Negatives – Civil War related (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Pickett, LaSalle Corbin (Gen. Pickett's widow) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Porter, Benjamin (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Porter, Gen. Fitz John (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Portraits, Civil War leaders (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Postcards (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Prisons (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Prison Camps, Confederate (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Railroads (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Randall, James G. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Reconstruction (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Reenactments (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Relic Hunters (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Reno, Major Marcus (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Rhode Island (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Richards, Almarin Nehemiah Cooley (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Robinson, George Foster (Sgt.) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Russell, Irwin, 'Private Notes' – copy, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Sanitary Commission (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbooks on Civil War (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sedgewick, General John (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Seminars,"Campaigning with Lee" (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Sharpshooters (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Shaw, Henry Wheeler (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Sheldon, Bert (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Shepherd, Alexander (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sheridan, Philip Henry (Lt. Gen.) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sherman, William T. (Gen.) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Shields, Gen. James (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Signals, Civil (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Soldiers of the Civil War, 4 prints, Princeton Printing Co., 1962 (Box 17)
  - South Carolina, Civil War (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Statistics, Civil War (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Stone, General Charles P. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Stonewall Brigade (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Strange, Col. John B. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Stratton Case (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Stuarts Cavalry (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Stuart, J.E.B. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tennessee (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Texas and Pacific Railway, Rates to Dallas and return for Confederate Veterans Reunion (Box 17)
  - Theatre, Civil War era (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - 31st Virginia Confederates (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Thomas, Benjamin P (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Thomas, Gen. George H., paper on (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Tobacco (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Tournier, Charles, Diary (N.Y. Lgt. Artillery) –typed (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tyrell, H. H. – RR pass, receipt, voucher and reunion ribbon (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Underground Railroad (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Union Army (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Union and Confederate Commander, Prints, 2 (Box 17)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Ursuline Convent, the Burning of (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Valley Campaign (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Veterans (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Vicksburg, paper by H. C. Westwood (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Virginia (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Virginia, Civil War (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Virginia, Historic Sites (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Virginia Military Institute (VMI) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Voorhees, Hon. D. W., 1863 Speech (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Washington, D. C., Civil War era (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Washington Light Guard, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Weapons (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - West, Civil War era (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - West Point, Civil War (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - West Virginia Tech (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Whitaker, Gen. Walter (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Whitman, Walt (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wilson Creek Nat'l Battlefield Park (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Winthrop, Theodore, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Women and the Civil War (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Zoaves (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Series II: Other Subject Files
  - American Revolution (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Army, United States (Box 5, Folder 2, Folder 1)
  - Assassinations (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Black Family – Geneology (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bookmarks (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cemeteries (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chattanooga Choo Choo (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chessie (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Conscription (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Custer, General George (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Economics and Warfare (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Files on City planning and Urban Development in Washington, D.C. (Box 21)
  - Forbes, Cecil (artist) Houses of Parliament (Box 14)
  - Frontier Military Posts, Southwest (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Grant, III, Lt. Col. U.S.S. Official Speeches, Articles (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Grant, III, Lt. Col. U. S. S., 1925-1928 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Harmon Memorial Lecture (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Hump Pilots (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Institute for Learning and Retirement (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Iroquois Club, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Kennedy, Pres. John F. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Loch Ness Monster (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Maps (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Mexican War (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Montpelier, A Brief History (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - New York Avenue Presbyterian Church (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Newspapers, 1880s-1890s (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Oldest Inhabitants of D. C., Assn. of (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Order of the Indian Wars (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Pledge of Allegiance (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Sandburg, Carl (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "TAPS" (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Tennessee, History of (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Texas (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Treasury Bond- Bon du Tresor, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - United Kingdom (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Vietnam (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Virginia, Fairfax County (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Washington Housing Assoc (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - White, Harry Decker (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - White House Photos (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - World War I (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - World War II (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Series III: Lincoln Materials
  - Anderson Cottage (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Anecdotes (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Assassination (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Azerodt, George A. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographies, Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Sketches (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Birth, Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Booth, John Wilkes (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons on Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clark, Allen C. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Colleges (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Commemorative Ceremonies (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Commentaries" (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Conspirators (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Corbett, Boston (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dinner Brochures (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Dog, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Education, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Elections (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Emancipation Proclamation Centenary (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Evans, George W. – friend of Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Finances, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Food, Lincoln and (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Forbes, Charles (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ford Theatre (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ford Theatre, Newspaper Clippings (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Funeral Train (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Gettysburg, Lincoln's Address (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Gettysburg Address print (Box 17)
  - Ghosts, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Hat, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Health, Lincoln's (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Inaugurations (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - International Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Isham, Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Kennedy/Lincoln – Comparisons of (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Lee and Lincoln prints, Civil War Times, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Legal Career (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Library of Congress Papers on Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Lincoln Bibliography (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln Bibliography (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "Lincoln Chronicle" (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Lincoln collectibles (Box 18)
  - "Lincoln Commission" (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Lincoln Commission Flag specifications and Lincoln Silhouttes (Box 17)
  - Lincoln Fellowship of Canada (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Lincoln Fellowship of Wisconsin (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Lincoln Group (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Lincoln Home, National Historic Site (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "Lincoln Legacy" (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Lincoln Legal Papers (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Lincoln, Abraham – letters (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Lincoln Log (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - "Lincoln Lore" (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Lincoln Lore, 1 – 1702 (Box 15)
  - Lincoln Lore, 1703-1840 (Box 16)
  - Lincoln Memorial (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln and Music of the Civil War (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "Lincoln and Negroes" – notes by E. Billings (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Lincoln, news clippings, 1927-1960 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln Newsletter (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln, notes and handwritten speeches by Billings (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Lincoln Pew (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lincoln, pictures (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Lincoln Speech on Sectionalism, copy of original (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Lincoln, Various articles about (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Lincolnian," 1957-1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Lincolnian," 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Lincolnian," 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mary Todd Lincoln Opera Committee – Opera 'Wing of Expectation.' (Box 17)
  - Mudd, Dr. Samuel A (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Murder Conspiracy (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Music on Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - New York Herald Planographic print, April 15, 1865 Lincoln Assassination (Box 17)
  - Paintings, Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Patents (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Payne, Lewis (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Peterson House (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Photographs on Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Portraits of Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Postcards (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Quotations (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Religion (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook on Lincoln, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Sculptures (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Sesquicentennial Abraham Lincoln Dinner Brochure, 1959 (Box 17)
  - "Sesquicentennial Intelligencer" (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Seward, William H. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Skits, Radio (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Speeches on Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Stamps, Postage (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Surratt, Mary (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Swatches reputedly taken from the lining of Lincoln's coffin (Box 14)
  - Theatre and Lincoln (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Tomb, Lincoln's (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Tourist Information (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Washington National Cathedral (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Youth, Lincoln's (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Series IV: Elden E. Billings - Personal Files
  - American Way of Life, notes by Elden Billings (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Billings, Mrs. Margaret (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Biographical, Billings (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Book Catalogs (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Book Catalogs, Old and Rare (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Book Purchases and Receipts (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Book Reviews (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Calendar, Personal (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cards, Greeting (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Catalog of Books in Billings Collection (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Certificates (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Certificate – Elden E. Billings for Meritorius Public Service Gov. of the District of Columbia, 1965 (Box 14)
  - College (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Civil War from Billings (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Civil War-related (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Centennial Commission (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Personal (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Dinner with Ike Program, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Geneology, Billings (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Gregor, Year Book of the Clan (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - High School, Billings (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Hohlweck, Phil J, Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Library of Congress Papers by Billings (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Military Career, Billings (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Photographs (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Photograph, Mr. and Mrs. Elden Billings (Box 14)
  - Photograph, Group (Box 14)
  - Photograph, Margaret Billings (Box 14)
  - "Planning": Speeches, Articles, Broadcasts, Etc (Box 21)
  - Post Cards (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Programs, Events (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Vest, Senator George Graham, Billings notes (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Series V: Publications
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Americana Illustrated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Banner (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Beauvoir (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Book Shopper (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Century Illustrated, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Century Magazine (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Civil War Centennial Commission (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Civil War Centennial Commission (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Civil War Monitor (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Civil War Press Corps (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Civil War Round Table Digest (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Civil War Round Table, Alexandria, VA (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Civil War Round Table, Illinois (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Civil War Round Table, Mississippi (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Civil War Round Table, Mississippi (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Civil War Round Table, Mississippi (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Civil War Round Table Obituaries (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Civil War Round Table, D.C (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Civil War Round Table, Others (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Civil War Society Newsletter (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Civil War Times (Box 9, Folder 23)